## JON S. POINTER

Phone: 970-980-7849 | Email: <u>jonpointer@msn.com</u> | Fort Collins, CO 80524 LinkedIn: <u>Linkedin.com/in/jon-pointer-pe-5317619a</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/JonPointer</u>

Portfolio: jonpointer.github.io/Portfolio

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a bootcamp Certificate and Bachelors and Masters degrees in Mechanical Engineering. Developed custom simulation tools, brought products to market, and worked with key customers through difficult situations. Demonstrated ability to work well with teams, deconstruct and solve difficult problems, and communicate across the spectrum with confidence and clarity.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, Visual Basic

**Applications:** GitHub, MySQL **Tools:** Node, jQuery, Bootstrap

#### **PROJECTS**

Retro Computer Quiz | github.com/JonPointer/Retro\_Computer\_Quiz | jonpointer.github.io/Retro\_Computer\_Quiz

- Summary: Quiz game with dynamic HTML generation, timer, and local storage
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Local Storage

# Weather Dashboard | github.com/JonPointer/Weather\_Dashboard | jonpointer.github.io/Weather\_Dashboard

- Summary: Weather dashboard, calls two APIs, dynamic HTML generation, local storage
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Local Storage, API

### **Search Assist**

### chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/search-assist/abnekaligdljpnkhenodalkmeejmbaph

- Summary: Chrome Extension, records desired pages, notes, and tags. Saves multiple searches and enables review, edit, additions, and export for documentation
- Role: Sole author. First self taught project
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Chrome Storage

# WhatsNotApp Messaging | github.com/JonPointer/whatsnotapp-messaging | whats-not-app.herokuapp.com

- Summary: Messaging application that stores messages and users, allowing filtering of past messages by user.
- Role: Team project. JavaScript, Routes, Socket.io implementation, MySQL calls
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, MySQL, Node

#### EXPERIENCE

# Principal Engineer - Technology Development Woodward, Inc.

2015-Present Fort Collins. CO

Corporate level Principal Engineer guiding new technology development across divisions. Primary technical contact with key industrial customers.

Key Accomplishments:

- Responsible for advancing electromagnetic technologies within Woodward Industrial Systems for inclusion in product development projects
- Create custom software tools and design guidelines to assist junior engineers in the development process
- Innovation award for most patent submissions for new actuation and valve technologies
- Facilitate company wide Electromechanical Actuation Innovation group

# Staff & Principal Engineer - Mechanical Development Woodward, Inc.

2005-2015

Fort Collins, CO

Lead project engineer responsible for requirements definition, customer interface, mechanical and electrical design, and validation. Senior engineer with mentoring responsibilities. Key Accomplishments:

- Developed electromechanical actuators and valves for industrial customers
- Lead project engineer and lead technical representative to primary customers
- Implemented new methods and software tools for vibration testing and analysis
- Created and continue to facilitate a company wide Mechanical Engineering Council

### **EDUCATION AND LICENSING**

### Bootcamp Certificate: University of Denver, Denver, CO

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering: Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO

**Licensed Professional Engineer**, Colorado License # 33017

#### VOLUNTEERING

School Board President and Treasurer: Mountain Sage Community School, 2012-Present

School Board President: River Song Waldorf School, 1998-2003

Mechanical Engineering Advisory Panel: Colorado State University, 2004-2016